Sindhuja Ramesh

Experience Summary

Overall 10 years of experienced in Global recruitment process, onboarding, process training, customer support/service, HR administration and recruitment, including with 4 years of recent experience in New Client Acquisitions, Niche Talent Acquisition, Client Development, payment follow-ups, Internal Staffs Recruitment, Executive Search, payroll handling.

Strong experience in Niche skill requirement hiring.

7years of experienced in US recruitment process, 3yrs in UK, APAC, Domestic, Australian recruitment.

Contact

8608818601 sindhuja.gpt@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/sindhuja- ramesh-764569b1 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Talent Management, Social Media Sourcing, Human Resources management, Negotiation, Onboarding, Labor legislation, compliance and grievance handling, Performance management, Time management, Incident management.

Languages

English Tamil, Malayalam, Hindi

Experience

Atrity Info Solutions Private Limited HR Manager Tiruchirappalli, Tamil Nadu, India

May 2023 - Mar 2024

Skills: End to end recruitment, Induction handling, onboarding, Payroll Processing, New Client Acquisitions, Niche Talent Acquisition, Client Development, payment follow-ups, Internal Staffs Recruitment, Executive Search

- Handling complete end to end recruitment, onboarding for internal hirings
- Handling Complaints and grievance, Labor legislation
- payroll handling in Keka
- Working Keka for Hiring, payroll, PMS
- Directly reporting to CEO
- Closely working with state and central government customer for HR Clearance and recruitment activity, complains for Contract engineers.

Dimiour (Vdart Inc) Client: TOYOTA HR Recruiter/Team lead Tiruchirappalli, Tamil Nadu, India

May 2021 - May 2023 (2 years 1 month)

- VDart Digital is now Dimiour: a digital technology company.
- Very good recruiting experience, Source, screen, interview and select qualified applicants for various IT requirements
- · Responsible for preparing review reports, recruitment reports, and submitting to the Management
- Responsible for the full recruitment life cycle; including checking references, negotiating pay, issuing offer letters, performing background checks and completing paperwork for internal hiring.
- Fill IT/Software positions with various clients on contract, contract-to-hire and permanent requirements across the USA.
- Responsible for W2, corp-to-corp (C2C), 1099 contract negotiations, completing the required documentation
- Utilize internal database to identify potential candidates
- Place job requirements on the Internet to increase available candidate pool
- Develop creative recruiting resources to attract qualified professionals interested in contract, contract to hire and direct placement employment Review job descriptions to understand the needs of the Client / Hiring Manager.
- Source and undercover candidates through job portals, connections, head- hunting, third party vendors, database, online communities, social networking sites.
- Working with Direct End clients as well as Implementation Partners for Technical requirements to fulfill their onsite consulting needs.
- Responsible for contract, contract-to-hire & full time placements of IT professionals for clients across the USA, Canada and Mexico
- Use effective resourcing strategies such as Portals -Dice, Monster, Career builder, Negotiating & finalizing

- salary/rate/hr aspects (W2 and Corp-Corp) with U.S. Citizen, H1B Etc.
- Share the resumes to the Client and follow up with feedback and interview process.
- Arranging interviews by coordinating schedules between client and candidates.
- Co-ordinate with hired candidates and check the DOJ, negotiate benefits and other on-boarding related queries.

247Headhunting

Client: HONDA, HYUNDAI, UNITED AIRLINES, HONEYWELL, FANUC ROBOTICS, etc.,

Technical Recruiter L2 Recruiter / Subject Matter Expert /Process Trainer Oct 2016 - Mar 2021 (4 years 8 months)Tiruchirappalli Area, India

- Oversee and organize per-scheduling of team(s)
- Trained in implementing new procedures and tactics to production floor on all levels of management
- Attended local Job Fairs: Staging, gathering potential candidates' information and directing individuals to our website
- Perform weekly one on one sessions with team members as well as conducting weekly team meetings
- Complete "side by sides" and "silent monitors" on a monthly basis for quality assurance
- Track performance and development
- Reply to emails on all level of concerns
- · Working on projects with speed, attentive to time lines, as well as maintained accuracy
- Directly interacted with Clients and end clients in detail about the requirements and the profiles of the submitted candidates.
- As a Senior Recruiter, led, managed and helped the entry level recruiters and trainee recruiters in team environment.
- Full life cycle recruitment services for fulfilling Contract technical positions across U.S.
- Extensive experience of Recruiting for candidates, per-screening to pull out quality potential candidates.
- Possess excellent knowledge of recruiting and hiring processes including sourcing, interviewing, reference checking, tracking, salary/rate negotiations, and closing.
- Have experience in dealing with all kind of authorization (US Citizen, GC, EAD, HIB etc.)
- Having an excellent track record of consultants which have been submitted to the clients, and have a good
 experience in creating an excel database of available consultants and clients and maintaining a complete
 information of the consultants and clients.
- Extensive experience in Job portals (i.e.: Monster.Com, Career Builder, Dice.Com, Indeed, Ladders and LinkedIn, Etc.).
- · Self-motivated professional who achieves results and has superior ability to coordinate
- Supported both IT & Non-IT positions
- Recruiting and hiring candidates in contract, contract-to-hire and permanent placements for multiple client companies.
- Filtering and reviewing completed candidate profiles, resumes and evaluated applicants work history, education and training, job skills, desired salary, hourly rate, and personal qualifications against open requirements.
- Developing and implementing effective recruiting strategies in order to attract, screen, recruit, and select high quality candidates including referral generation, ad placement, position postings, direct sourcing, cold calling and networking to develop a qualified pool of candidates.
- Establishing and maintaining solid working relationships with hiring managers.

Precision Infomatic (M) Private limited Human Resources Assistant TRICHY

December 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 4 months)

Doing HR administrative work as well as worked as a service desk executive @precisioninfomatic madras IT pvt ltd in Trichy branch

Handling engineering conveyance in servicefirst tool and doing basic office administrative works

Taking care of grievance complaints and resolving the cases Ticket escalations.

Handling the phone calls and checking the status of the cases.

Handling the SERVICE FIRST cases (customer relationship management) and closing the cases.

Raising the service desk tickets and assign the concern engineer and by end of the day try to close.

Preparing daily report and monthly report and submitting to manager Handling the mail complaints and replying with resolution.

Page 2 of 5

Handling the MS outlook configurations Uploading the packets through upload portal Tickets and assigning to the concern team Ticketing Tools: Service first, BMC Remedy, Prism.

First source Solution private limited Customer Service Associate TRICHY

August 2013 - October 2014 (1 year 3 months)

- It is a busy call center environment- Vodafone Telecom Process Handle customer inquiries, complaints, billing questions and payment extension/service requests.
- Calm angry callers, repair trust, locate resources for problem resolution and design best-option solutions.
- · Interface daily with internal partners in accounting, field services, new business operations and
- · consumer affairs.
- Tagging and working in Oracle CRM and Genesis database.

Education

Bharathidasan University, Tiruchirappalli Master of Human Resources Management, MHRM

Bharathiar University
Bachelor of computer application, BCA